ANAND AGGARWAL

2nd Year MChem with Industrial Placement Student

Email: anand@anandaggarwal.co.uk

Phone: 07769 710298

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/anand-aggarwal12/

Address: Teddington, TW11 8DX

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a self-motivated student with a strong interest in coding and data analysis, participating in various coding competitions for the past 8 years and completing numerous data courses. My experience in project management and data analytics spans many years. As a result, I already have a strong understanding of different roles within an organisation and the skills required to communicate effectively across teams.

I enjoy playing & watching sports such as football and tennis in my free time. I am a big mini-golf player and look to play as much as possible and I also try to visit/volunteer at the theatre when I get the chance.

EDUCATION

2020 - present **MChem Chemistry with Industrial Placement**

University of Bath

Finished 1st Year with 68% average (2:1)

1st Year Units:	Grade:	2 nd Year Units:	Grade:	
The chemistry of everyday things General practical chemistry From molecules to materials Foundation chemistry laboratory	75% 71% 68% 63%			
Fundamentals of organic chemistry Atomic structure, bonding, and the Periodic Table	60%			
Introduction to environmental and sustainable chemistry	74%			
Kingston Grammar School				
A Levels in Physics, Chemistry, Maths, Further Maths and EPQ - A*, A*, A*, A, A*				

2013 - 2020

GCSEs - 6 A*, 3 A, B

WORK EXPERIENCE

ROLE COMPANY DATES

Association of Corporate Treasurers July 2021 Data Analyst

Reviewed customer journeys and behaviours when students registered for and completed units/ passed exams. Examined whether there were any trends in a sample and, once presented to management, I expanded my analysis to the full dataset. The analysis was used by the finance team to produce more accurate forecasts and by the qualifications team to target which units require more support for students.

Academic Tutor Manning's Tutors

November 2020 – Present

As a tutor within the National Tutoring Programme (NTP), I work with disengaged and disadvantaged students in Maths and Science to catch up on lost learning due to the pandemic. With tuition only provided online, I had to be imaginative in ways to captivate students and flexible to each students learning style.

Head of IT Cash, Currency & Payments Ltd

September 2017 – Present

I worked on developing an easy to implement PowerBI dashboard that consultants could use. This enabled consultants not only to save time by having clear visual reports in real time, but also created a more efficient and on-demand service for the client.

Director Anand's Tech Support

April 2019 – January 2021

I created online profiles for small, local companies and enabled them to capture online business through bespoke websites, inventory management systems, and payment systems. This allowed businesses to respond to the pandemic quickly and profitably.

SKILLS

SKILL	DESCRIPTION	EVIDENCE
Coding	Proficient in HTML , CSS , SQL & Python . Adept at designing/developing databases and data analysis.	Winner of Young Rewired State Most Innovative Design 2014. Internship at the ACT.
Data Analysis	Adept at cleaning and identifying trends within sample sets. Experienced at extending to large data sets and writing up observations and recommendations.	Certificates: Microsoft Azure AI AI-900 ☐ Microsoft Azure Data DP-900 ☐ Internship at the ACT
Data Presentation	Collation of UX and consumer behaviour for businesses to tailor online experiences using Google Analytics. Presentation of complex data sets in an accessible report for management to take decisions.	Using skills acquired from Azure & Tableau courses to identify trends in datasets. Presented to management using PowerBI.
Project Management	Exceptional time management skills. Experienced at managing a team under high pressure situations and achieving goals for key stakeholders.	Stage Manager for 6 productions, including at the Edinburgh Fringe Festival 2019. Director of successful web design business.
Coaching	Private Tutor for over three years, building a great rapport with students. Achieved measured success, increasing attainment by 35%.	Qualification for Tutors CPD; Qualified Tutor

REFERENCES

Available on Request.